Guide to the Jody Fischer Collection of Willie Nelson
The Wittliff Collections
- Audio Cassette Tapes, 1976-1995
  - Willie Nelson Recordings, undated
    - One side labeled "Willie Some Enchanted Evening" other side labeled "1. Red Dirt Highway 2. The Old Man of 87 3. It Got Me This Far" and "Willn'David/David'N'Will Music Contact Jeff Carlton 615-320-7323" (Some Enchanted Evening side starts with Moon River, so is a different album from the back side.), undated (Box 5)
    - "'Songwriter' Album" Side A –" Songwriter, Crossing the Border, Who'll Buy My Memories, Down To Her Socks, Eye of the Storm, Nobody Said" Side B – "How Do You Feel, Write Your Own Song, Under the Gun, Final Attraction, Good Times" (second side seems blank), undated (Box 5)
    - "Stagecoach by Willie Nelson" "& D.A.COE" (music on one side only), undated (Box 5)
    - "Stardust" (scribbled out label on both sides appears to be re-recorded), undated (Box 5)
    - "Texas Willie" (Other side features an unknown female voice), undated (Box 5)
    - "Texas in My Soul – Willie Nelson", undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie" (2 copies), undated (Box 5)
    - A) "Linda Rondstadt Don't Cry Now" B) "Willie – Yesterday's Wine" (Sides are labeled wrong – labels read the opposite.) Cassette sleeve reads: Side A) "Sleepy Day, Forever was made for love, Ramblin', This is My Life, When I Fall Asleep & Dream, Open My Heart, Kill the Beast, I'm Ready to Go, 90 M.P.H., Back YardSide B)Two Legged Clucky, Ironweed, Lady on the Trail, Col. McKenzie, If I Were a Mountain, Feed Me Now I'm Hungry, Angel's Form, Sparking Friends, Butterfly, Father I Need Shelter", undated (Box 5)
    - A) "Willie Nelson" B) "Rita Coolidge", undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie Tenderly" – opposite side labeled "7-8-9pm Rodney Crowell" (is re-recorded 4/19 Ray Palla is crossed out on both sides of the cassette), undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie & Family Live" (Sides 1 and 2, 3 and 4), undated (Box 5)
    - "My Way – Frank & Willie" (After that song it is Paula, Amy Charlie's Angels Tape 1 and has the girls playing Charlie's Angels and recordings of Willie singing with the girls – Amy Lee Nelson and Paula Carline Nelson), undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie and Freddie" (likely either Freddie Powers or Freddie Fender – he has recorded with them both), undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie W/ Grady", undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie, Kris, Dolly – Monument Album" "Program One – You're Gonna Love Yourself (In the Morning), Ping Pong, You'll Always Have Someone, Here Comes that Rainbow Again, The Bigger the Fool, the Harder the Fall, Everything's Beautiful (in its Own Way), Bring on the Sunshine, Put it Off Until Tomorrow, I Never Cared for You, Casey's Last Ride Program Two – Help me Make it Through the Night, Happy Happy Birthday Baby, You left me A Long, Long Time Ago, To Make a Long Story Short, She's Gone, Someone Loves you Honey, King of a Lonely Castle, The Little Things, The Bandits of Beverly Hills, What do you Think About Lovin', Born to Love Me", undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie & Jackie", undated (Box 5)
    - "Willie + Merle Session (Always on My Mind)" Other side: "Saynday Stories" (Stories of the Plains Indians – Saynday is the name of a character), undated (Box 5)
    - "Merle & Willie" other side "Pancho & Lefty", undated (Box 6)
    - "Willie, Merle, Freddie" and "Merle, Willie & Freddie", undated (Box 6)
    - "Are There Anymore Real Cowboys? Neil Young & Willie Nelson", undated (Box 6)
    - "Willie – Neil Young Leon" (Case is labeled "Highwayman"), undated (Box 6)
    - Randy Travis Duets Heros + Friends (sic) (Willie collaborates on "Birth of the Blues"), undated (Box 6)
    - "Shelby Lynne & Willie Nelson" – case reads – "The Nearness of You, I'm the One to Blame, It Had to be You, You Can't Break My Heart, Little Red Wagon, Smoke Gets in Your Eyes, Misery, Stormy Weather, Mockingbird Hill, Till the God of the World, Valentine, No One Will Ever Know, I Can't Begin to Tell You, The Kind of Love I Can't Forget", undated (Box 6)
    - Texans United Concert" (Case says "Willie – Borderline") A) "One More Time" Doc. Poolus(?)/Ken Hirsch "Happy Hard Times" DP, DR, John 212-580-7784 B) Willie, Waylon, Kris & Johnny - Case reads Highwaymen For More Information Call Annette Harrison 264-0222 – (Cassette possibly re-recorded to be what side 2 is labelled.), undated (Box 6)
    - A) Willie, Waylon, Kris, and Johnny B) Clyde Buchanan (is blank, taped over the labels – 2-3 stacked. Appears to be a Highwaymen recording), 1983 (Box 6)
    - A) Willie, Waylon, Kris, & Johnny B) "One More Time", undated (Box 6)
  - Recordings by Other Artists, 1982-1986, undated
    - "Roseanne Cash", March 21, 1986 (Box 6)
    - "Roseanne Cash/ Bruce Springsteen" "Seven Year Ache" and "The E Street Shuffle", undated (Box 6)
    - "Ray Live Dallas" and "Ray Charles", undated (Box 6)
    - "Ray Charles Christmas", undated (Box 6)
    - "Rita Coolidge", undated (Box 6)
    - "Under Arrest Miles Davis/ Harvest Neil Young", undated (Box 6)
    - "Dylan Angel Flying", undated (Box 6)
    - "Bob Dylan Knocked Out Loaded", undated (Box 6)
    - "Joe Eli – Live @ Liberty Lunch, undated (Box 6)
    - "Elvis – Sun Sessions - Memphis Band Jam", October 1982 (Box 6)
    - "Jimmy Dale Gilmore Spinning Around the Sun/ Hal Ketchum Past the Point of Rescue", undated (Box 6)
    - "Merle Haggard It's All in the Game", undated (Box 6)
    - "Emmy Lou Harris/Billy Joe Shaver", undated (Box 6)
    - "The Headlights "Test the Spirit" Demo recorded at Willie Nelson's studio", undated (Box 6)
    - "Imagine" (original label of "Forgotten Eyes" is crossed out – it is a recording of the Beatles Imagine), undated (Box 6)
    - "BorderLord Shake Hands with the Devil - Kris", undated (Box 6)
    - "Kris & Rita", undated (Box 6)
    - "Kris Ruffs", August 10, 1985 (Box 6)
    - "Jody and the Kid Kris Kristofferson (monument)", undated (Box 6)
    - "Delbert McClinton "The Jealous Kind" "Plain From the Heart", undated (Box 6)
    - "Mickey Newbury- New Material", undated (Box 6)
    - "Lee Oskar/Ray Charles", undated (Box 6)
    - "Bonnie Raitt – The Glow" and "Delbert McClinton Keeper of the Flame/ Dan Fogelberg", undated (Box 6)
    - "Hand to Mouth – Mickey Raphael", undated (Box 6)
    - "Lionel Richie Can't Slow Down", undated (Box 6)
    - "Sade Diamond Life/ Whitney Houston", undated (Box 6)
    - "Santana & Booker", undated (Box 6)
    - "Soul Music" ("Bruce Springsteen" is crossed out), undated (Box 6)
    - "Bruce Springsteen", undated (Box 6)
    - "Bruce Springsteen Born in the USA", undated (Box 7)
    - "West Texas Songwriters Special Austin City Limits 8/31/82" and "With Butch Hancock, Townes Van Zandt, David Halley, Jimmie Gilmore", August 31, 1982 (Box 7)
    - "Neil Young New Album", undated (Box 7)
    - "Neil Young – Live", August 1985 (Box 7)
    - "Neil Young – Mother Earth Don Henley – 7AIV", August 1985 (Box 7)
- Video Cassette Tapes, 1982-1995, undated
  This series consists of VHS and U-Matic tapes. Most of the tapes are programs featuring Willie Nelson recorded from television. The programs include news interviews, music concerts, television shows and film. The majority of the tapes are produced video although, there are some tapes featuring raw footage of Willie Nelson. The raw footage includes a music performance at a bar in 1990, the auction of Willie Nelson's personal belongings, Willie Nelson performing at Phoenix Indian School and Willie Nelson performing a toast to Mae Boren Axton. The raw footage tapes have been copied onto DVDs.
  The collection also includes television recordings of Farm Aid 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 that aired on the MTV network. The VHS tapes that do not feature Willie Nelson include two episodes of Ned Blessing, a raw footage recording of the play, Small Town Girl and a raw footage recording of a tribal award ceremony with Kris Kristoferson in attendance. Titles supplied by Jody Fischer are in quotations.
  This series is divided into five subseries: Farm Aid Concerts, Farm Aid Related Videos, Willie Nelson Produced Video, Willie Nelson Raw Footage and Non-Willie Nelson.
  - Farm Aid Concerts, 1985-1986
    - "Elvis-Graceland- 0515 Farm Aid-MTV." [Farm Aid 1]. VHS. (Box 7)
    - "Farm Aid 1." ["Moon-network written on inside of tape]. VHS (Box 7)
    - "Farm Aid II." VHS (Box 7)
    - "FA II." [Farm Aid II]. VHS (Box 7)
    - "FA II." [Farm Aid II]. VHS (Box 7)
    - "Farm Aid II: The Concert for America; Full Show." VHS (Box 7)
    - "Farm Aid II Nontagable :25 min Produced by MTV networks Inc." U-Matic, June 19, 1985 (Box 7)
    - "Farm Aid II tix :30." U-Matic (Box 7)
    - "Farm Aid II' Nontagable :25 Produced by MTV Networks Inc." U-Matic, June 19, 1985 (Box 7)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 9AM-10AM 60:00 10AM-11AM 60:00." VHS (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 11am-12noon 60:00 12noon-1pm-60:00 #87217MB." VHS, August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 1pm-2pm 60:00 2pm-3pm 60:00 #87217MB." VHS, August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 3pm-4pm 60:00 4pm-5pm #87217MB " VHS, August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 5pm-6pm 60:00 6pm-7pm 60:00 #8721MB." VHS (2 copies), August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 7pm-8pm 60:00 8pm-9pm 60:00 #87396LL" VHS. (2 copies), August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 9pm-10pm 60:00 10pm-11pm 60:00 #87217MB." VHS, August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 11pm-12am 60:00 12am-1am 60:00 #87217MB." VHS, August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "MTV Networks Inc. Farm Aid II 1am-2am 60:00 2am-3am 60:00 #87217MB." VHS, August 12, 1986 (Box 8)
    - "Farm-Aid III Hours #1, #2." VHS (Box 8)
    - "Farm-Aid III Hours 3 & 4." VHS (Box 8)
    - "Farm-Aid III Hours 5 & 6." VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm-Aid III Hours 7 & 8." VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm-Aid III Hour 9 & 10." VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm Aid IV Special." VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm Aid V 4:30-7:15pm Mark Chestnut." VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm Aid V Finale." [Spine label says Memphis Belle]. VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm Aid V 7:15-10:20pm Neil Young." VHS (Box 9)
  - Farm Aid Related Videos, 1986, 1995, undated
    - "American Farmer." Produced by Edd Louisiana, U-Matic (Box 9)
    - "American Summer Picnic." [Benefit for Farm Aid II. Recorded off television]. VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm Aid One Year Later. The Rock'n Roll Evening News." Produced by Andy Friendly Productions, VHS (Box 9)
    - "Farm Crisis: The Black Experience." Federation of Southern Cooperative (Box 9)
    - "Farm Features." Produced by David G. Smith Productions. VHS (Box 10)
    - "Fresh from the Family Farm; Where Our Food Comes From." Produced by ZMedia Inc. VHS, 1995 (Box 10)
    - "Jessica Lange- Farm Aid promos Version 1-Take 1 Version 2-Take 12 Version 3 – Take 1 Rough-Unedited." [Three takes of Jessica Lange doing Farm Aid promotions]. VHS (Box 10)
    - CBS Records 1. Raw Footage of Local Press Conference. 2. Local Network affiliates stories of Ref. Suit. 3.Raw Footage Mark Frick, one of the Plaintiffs. [Video contains raw footage of Farm Aid Press conference]. Produced by Opryland Productions, VHS (Box 10)
    - "Torn from the Land Farm video." VHS (Box 10)
    - United Farmer and Rancher Congress Selected Version 120 mins. [Raw footage of United Farmer and Rancher Congress]. VHS, September 11-13, 1986 (Box 10)
    - UFRC Sept. 11-13, 1986 Vol. I. [Raw footage of United Farmer and Rancher Congress]. VHS, September 11-13, 1986 (Box 10)
    - UFRC Sept. 11-13, 1986 Vol. II. [Raw footage of United Farmer and Rancher Congress]. VHS, September 11-13, 1986 (Box 10)
    - UFRC Sept. 11-13, 1986 Vol. III. [Raw footage of United Farmer and Rancher Congress]. VHS, September 11-13, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Willie Nelson Videos, 1982-1993, undated
    - "Austin City Limits Willie, Kris, Waylon, Billy Joe & Kimmie Roy Orbison/ Ray Charles." VHS, August 5, 1982 (Box 10)
    - "BAD TV Best of Songwriter Vol II." [Includes recording of a NBC news program; Willie Nelson interview on Evening Magazine; and a BADTV episode featuring Willie Nelson]. (Box 10)
    - "BAD TV Best of Songwriter Vol IV." VHS (Box 10)
    - "BAD TV goes to the CMA Awards." VHS, 1983 (Box 10)
    - "Campbell-Ewald US Space Foundation Press Conference Reel 22 Spots See Enclosed List."[Willie Nelson performs with Frank Sinatra]. VHS, September 25, 1987 (Box 11)
    - "The Making of Red Headed Stranger #68344." VHS (Box 11)
    - "MTV NETWORKS INC. Willie Nelson Special (Stereo) 60:00 6/30/86 #85557." VHS, June 30, 1986 (Box 11)
    - "MTV NETWORKS INC. Willie Nelson Interview 33:00 #87226." VHS, August 11, 1986 (Box 11)
    - "Meet the Press." U-Matic, September 22, 1985 (Box 11)
    - "Pancho & Lefty Willie Nelson/Merle Haggard." Produced by Me & Paul Productions Films Ltd., VHS, 1983 (Box 11)
    - "The Picnic 1985." [BADTVs coverage of the music concert- The Picnic, includes behind the scenes footage recorded off TV]. VHS (Box 11)
    - "Red Headed Stranger." VHS, June 5, 1986 (Box 11)
    - "1. Two for Texas 2. Behind the Music VH1 Willie 3. Storytellers with J. Cash." [Spine label reads "Houston Houston Houston"]. VHS, undated (Box 11)
    - "Up Close and Personal Willie." [Local news interview with Willie Nelson recorded off TV]. VHS, undated (Box 11)
    - "VH-1 Willie Nelson Guest VJ 9pm-10pm 6/30." VHS, undated (Box 11)
    - "VH-1 Willie Nelson GVJ 9p-10p 2/3 Karen L/Alexander." VHS, undated (Box 12)
    - "We Are the World/Wild Horses of America." VHS., undated (Box 12)
    - "Willie-20/20 ABC." VHS, undated (Box 12)
    - "Willie's Birthday '93." [Recorded off TV]. Produced by NBC, VHS, 1993 (Box 12)
    - "Willie Hosts Saturday Night Live Plus BADTV Shorts Jody." VHS, February 1987 (Box 12)
    - "Willie Nelson And Family HBO Special." VHS, April 1983 (Box 12)
    - "Willie Nelson Jimmy's Road." Produced by Ozark Film & Video, VHS, April 1983 (Box 12)
    - "Willie Nelson - Home Again." Produced by KBVO-TV, VHS, June 6, 1984 (Box 12)
    - "Willie Nelson/Neil Young Are There Anymore Real Cowboys." Produced by Lana Nelson Productions, VHS, August 1, 1985 (Box 12)
    - "The Willie Nelson Special Original Unedited Program Willie-Ray Charles Jackie King." VHS, May 17, 1984 (Box 12)
    - "Willie Nelson Special." VHS, undated (Box 12)
    - "Willie - New Years Eve." VHS, December 31, 1984 (Box 12)
    - "Willie Prime Time IRS." VHS., July 18, 1991 (Box 12)
    - "Willie/Wrangler Music Invitational" VHS. [Willie Nelson concert presented by Wrangler recorded off TV]., November 1986 (Box 13)
    - "'90 XMAS Willie & Kris Spoke 190." [Raw footage of a musical performance by Willie Nelson at a bar]. VHS, 1990 (Box 13)
    - "Bad TV & Just Bill At the Auction." [Raw footage of an auction of Willie Nelson and Connie Nelson's personal property]. VHS, January 23, 1991 (Box 13)
    - "Mae Boren Axton Toast." [Raw footage of a tribute to Mae Boren Axton at the Vanderbilt Plaza Hotel. Willie Nelson gives a toast.] VHS, February 15, 1988 (Box 13)
    - "Willie Nelson Promo." [Various recordings taped from TV of Willie Nelson performances]. VHS, undated (Box 13)
    - "Willie Nelson visits Phoenix Indian School." [Raw footage of Willie Nelson performing at Phoenix Indian School]. VHS, February 24, 1987 (Box 13)
  - Non-Willie Nelson Videos, 1985, undated
    - "Ned Blessing Pilot 91 Daniel Baldwin Chris Cooper." [Episode recorded off TV]. VHS, 1991 (Box 13)
    - "Ned Blessing." [Episode recorded off TV]. VHS, undated (Box 13)
    - "Small Town Girl." [Play starring Kimmie Rhodes]. Produced by GlennGlenn Productions Inc., VHS, undated (Box 13)
    - "Willie Nelson, Kris Kristofferson, Mak Gaiz Benefit/Banquet/News Conf." [Raw footage of tribal award ceremony thanking Willie Nelson (does not appear in video). Kris Kristoferson is a guest panelist]. VHS, November 5, 1985 (Box 13)
- Artifacts, 1974-1989, undated
  The bulk of the series are T-shirts, sweatshirts, jackets and hats. Most of the T-Shirts are from Farm Aid, the 4th of July Picnic, and other concerts with some from various running events, and a few from the Austin Opry House. The four sweatshirts are from Farm Aid. The jackets include paraphernalia from Willie Nelson concerts, Pederanales Recording Studio, and the 1984 Darrel and Willie Invitational. There are two hats; one white hat with "Willie Nelson Luck Texas," on the band, and one baseball cap with "Willie Nelson Who'll Buy My Memories? The IRS Tapes," on the front. Also included in this series is a variety of items including match boxes, pins, golf balls fans, and bumper stickers.
  - Farm Aid pin, "I'm Willie's Friend" pin, Farm Aid bandanas (2), Backstage passes, Tickets, "Willie Nelson for President" fan, Bumper stickers (2), Willie Nelson golf balls (3), Packs of Willie Nelson matches (8), Willie Nelson backstage pass key chain, undated (Box 14)
  - T-Shirts & Sweatshirts (1 of 3), 1985, 1987, undated (Box 15)
    Farm Aid. Black T-Shirt. Farm Aid IV. Black T-Shirt. Farm Aid. White T-Shirt. 1987. Farm Aid. Black T-Shirt. 1985. arm Aid III. Yellow T-Shirt. Farm Aid II. Tan T-Shirt. Farm Aid. Grey T-Shirt. 1985. Farm Aid. White Sweat Shirt. Farm Aid II. Gray Sweat Shirt. "Farm Aid II Keep America Growing." Picture of tractor and American flag. "Farm Aid Keep America Growing." [Front]. Farm Aid University Memorial Stadium Champaign Illinois September 22, 1985."
  - T-Shirts & Sweatshirts (2 of 3), 1974-1987, undated (Box 16)
    4th of July Picnic. Dark Blue T-Shirt. 1975. 4th of July Picnic. Yellow T-Shirt. 1976. 4th of July Picnic. Blue and White T-Shirt. 1985. 3rd annual 4th of July Picnic. White and Yellow T-Shirt. 4th of July Picnic with Armadillo. 1987. 4th of July Picnic. Red T-Shirt. 1976 4th of July Picnic. White and Yellow T-Shirt. 1974. 4th of July Picnic. White and Yellow T-Shirt. 1974. 4th of July Picnic. Blue and White T-Shirt. 1979. 4th of July Picnic. Blue and White T-Shirt. 1978. 4th of July Picnic with American Flag. Blue and White T-Shirt.
  - T-Shirts & Sweatshirts (3 of 3), 1977-1989, undated (Box 17)
    "Opening Celebration Lone Star Records Austin Opry House June 19, 1978." [Front]. White Ringer Tee.
    "Austin Opry House Grand Opening Presents Willie Nelson and Family Special Guest Ol' Whats-His-Name June 28, 1977." [Front]. White Ringer Tee.
    "Willie Nelson and Many Others." Picture of Texas with tennis shoes. [Front]. Black T-Shirt.
    Willie Nelson's Whiskey River." Picture of Texas with tennis shoes. [Front]. Brown T-Shirt.
    Picture of Willie Nelson in flying tennis shoe. [Front]. Black T-Shirt.
    "The Willie Nelson Running Society 11th Annual Birthday Run April 29th, 1989 Atlanta GA." Picture of Georgia with American Flag. [Front]. Blue Tank Top.
    "Willie (no head no backstage pass." Picture of a road. [Front]. Black T-Shirt.
    "Willie and Family On the Road Again." [Front]. Black T-Shirt.
    "Willie and Family On the Road Again." [Front]. Black Sleeveless T-Shirt.
    "Thanks from Willie and the Boys." [Front]. "Stage Hand." Picture of five Armadillos carrying giant speaker. [Back]. Blue T-Shirt.
    "Stage Hand." Picture of five Armadillos carrying giant speaker. [Front]. "Thanks from Willie and the Boys." [Back]. White Baseball Tee with blue sleeves.
    "Willie Nelson at the Golden Nugget Las Vegas." [Front]. White T-Shirt.
    "It's Still Not Weird Enough for Me! Songwriter." [Front]. "It's All Wrong Change It!" [Back]. Grey T-Shirt.
    "Willie Nelson Red Headed Stranger." [Front]. White T-Shirt.
    "Willie Nelson for President." [Front]. White T-Shirt.
    Picture of Texas with Willie's face. [Front]. Black T-Shirt.
  - Jackets (1 of 2), undated (Box 18)
    "Jody." [Front]. "Willie and Family On the Road Again." [Back]. Black Jacket. "Songwriter." [Back]. Black Jacket with yellow horizontal stripes. Willie Nelson & Family in Concert HBO." [Back]. Black jacket.
  - Jackets (2 of 2), 1984, undated (Box 19)
    "Wrangler Jeans Willie Nelson & Family." [Front]. "Wranger." [Back]. Grey Jacket with blue and yellow stripes.
    "John." [Front]. "Pedernales Recording Studio Cut 'N Putt." [Back]. Brown
    Jacket with navy blue stripe. "1984 Darrell & Willie Invitational." [Front]. Navy Blue Jacket.
  - Hats, undated (Box 20)
    "Willie Nelson Luck Texas." White hat with black band
    "Willie Nelson "Who'll Buy My Memories? The IRS Tapes 1-800-652-3400." Black baseball cap with white front